A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Vice President, Rodney W. Nichols FA144
Rockefeller Archive Center
- AAAS, 1969-1973; 3; 0.2 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  - AAAS, 1970-1973; folder 5 of 5 (Box 21, Folder 17)
- Corporations, 1970-1975; 4; 0.6 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Includes primarily correspondence; also includes curriculum vita, notes, background information, proposals, grant information, memoranda, newspaper clippings, and receipts.
  - Fondazione Giovanni Agnelli, 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - American Electric Power Company, Inc., 1972 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - American Swiss Credit Co. Ltd., 1973 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Atlantic Richfield Foundation, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Banks, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Becton, Dickinson & Co., 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Chase Manhattan Bank, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - CIBA-GEIGY Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Citibank [1st National City Bank], 1972 1974 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc., 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Corporate Grants [gen. info], 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Harvey Dann Company, Inc., 1972-1973 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Digital Equipment Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Dillon Read & Co., 1974 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - E.I. DuPont de Nemours & Company, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - The Equitable Life Assurance Society of the United States, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Exxon [Standard Oil Co], 1971-1974 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - General Foods Corporation, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Hoffman-La Roche, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - IBM, 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Marathon Oil Company, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Merck & Company, 1971 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Metropolitan Life, 1970 1972-1974 (Box 22, Folder 24)
  - Mobil Foundation, Inc., 1973-1975 (Box 22, Folder 25)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 26)
  - New York Life Insurance Company, 1973-1974 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - The Prudential Insurance Company of America, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Research Corporation, 1971-1972 1974 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Rhone-Poulenc [Rhodia], 1973 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - RU Council, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Research Instruments, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Sears, Roebuck & Company, 1973 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Squibb Corporation, 1973-1974 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Standard Oil Company, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Sun Oil Company, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - J. R Taft Corporation, 1971-1973 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Texaco Inc., 1974 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Texas Instruments Foundation, 1971-1974 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - TRW Inc., 1974 (Box 23, Folder 13)
- Development Files, 1971-1974; 5; 0.8 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Includes donor lists, notes, correspondence, grant lists, and receipts.
  - Development Committee Contributions, 1971-1974 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Development Personnel, 1974 (Box 23, Folder 15)
- Correspondence, 1970-1972; 6; 0.8 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Includes primarily correspondence; also includes reimbursement vouchers, employment applications, curriculum vita, itineraries, memoranda, and budget estimates.
  Arranged in chronological order by month and year.
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 April-May (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 June (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 July (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 August (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 September (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 October (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 November (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 December (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 January (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 February (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 March (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 April (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 May (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 June (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 July (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1970 August 1971 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 September (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 October (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 November (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1971 December (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 January (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 February (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 March (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 April (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 May (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 June (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 July (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 August (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 September (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 October (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 November (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Chronological Correspondence Files, 1972 December (Box 25, Folder 10)
- General Files, 1967-1980; 7; 0.8 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Includes primarily correspondence, reviews of books and articles, grant proposals, reports, curriculum vita, clippings, articles, notes, memoranda, and programs.
  - General Files: A (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - General Files: B, 1970-1975 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - General Files: C, 1970-1975 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - General Files: D, 1970-1975 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - General Files: E, 1970-1974 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - General Files: F, 1970-1976 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - General Files: G, 1970-1975 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - General Files: H, 1970-1975 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - General Files: I, 1973-1974 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - General Files: J, 1970 1974-1975 1980 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - General Files: K, 1970-1975 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - General Files: L, 1970-1976 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - General Files: M, 1970-1975 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - General Files: N, 1970-1971 1974-1975 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - General Files: O, 1970-1973 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - General Files: P, 1967 1970-1976; folder 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - General Files: P [Morton Printz], 1970-1975; folder 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - General Files: Q, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - General Files: R, 1970-1975 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - General Files: S, 1970-1975 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - General Files: T, 1971-1975 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - General Files: V, 1972-1975 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - General Files: W, 1969-1975 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - General Files: Y & Z, 1970-1973 (Box 27, Folder 10)
- Iran Files, 1962-1977; 8; 3.3 Cubic Feet Extent is approximate
  Includes primarily curriculum vita and correspondence; also includes proposals for university, articles and clippings, correspondence, planning reports, itineraries, travel information, brochures, employment applications, reports, job advertisements, curricula information and reports, notes, site information for university, receipts, memoranda, and material in Farsi.
  Includes a section that is arranged in alphabetical order.
  - Iran Files: Letters with & without catalogs, and builders, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 1 of 11 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 2 of 11 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 3 of 11 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 4 of 11 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 5 of 11 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 6 of 11 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 7 of 11 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 8 of 11 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 9 of 11 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 10 of 11 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files: Applications, 1975; folder 11 of 11 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files: Reports [A Report to Imperial Government of Iran], 1974 September (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files: [Publications of Dr. M.A. Ghalambor], 1962-1974 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files: The Harvard Crimson June, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Iran Files: Iran (Persia) by Seyyed Hossein Nasr [Inscription to President Frederick Seitz from author on inside cover], 1973 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files: General Background, 1971 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files: Reports [An Analysis of U.S.-Iranian Cooperation in Higher Education], 1976 November (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files: Correspondence [with Amouzegar and the Shah], 1974-1975 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files: Reports [Draft Report, Salary and Econ Data Questions, and Morton's Reply], 1975 January-February (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files: Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Iran Files: Rockefeller Delegation Itinerary and Travel Brochures, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Iran Files: Miscellaneous Files, 1968 1973-1975 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Iran Files: Information on Iranian law of charitable organization, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Iran Files: Letters of Introduction from David Rockefeller, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Iran Files: Letters and Telegrams, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Iran Files: Seminar on the Problems of Training Medical and Health Personnel, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Iran Files: [in Persian] (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Iran Files: Pahlavi University - Physiology Department [Publications of Dr. Mahmood Tabatabai], 1970 1972-1974 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Iran Files: Pahlavi University [Department of Anatomical Sciences-Publication Reprints] (some in German), 1962-1974 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files: Pahlavi University [Reprints and Reports], 1966-1974 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files: Pahlavi University [Publications by Dr. M. Vessal and Dr. A. Vassef], 1969-1974 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files: Publications of Dr. Taghi Fakouhi (Pahlavi University), 1971-1974 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files: Working Group Meetings, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Amirdivani, Said, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Amouzegar, Jamshid, 1974-1976 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Badie, James, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Beam, Alexander, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Beigi, Dr. F. Ismail, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Board/Council/Candidates, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Boyadjian, Haig J., 1975 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Burroughs, Franklin T., 1975 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Chapman, Dr. Albert, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Choppin, Purnell, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Darbani, Mohsen, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Djavadi, Dr. Fereydoun, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Esso Middle East, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Farmanfarmain, Allhaverdi, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Farpour, A., MD, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Ghani, Cyrus, Esq, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Goodarzi, Mohsen M., 1975 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Hairstone, 1975 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Hatefi, Youssef, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: His Imperial Majesty Reza Shah Aryamehr, 1975-1977 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Hoveida, Amir-Abbas, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: General Background, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 27)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: International Basic Economy Corporation, 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 28)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Iranian Contacts/Consultants, 1974-1975 (Box 31, Folder 29)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Iranian Dinner, 1974 November 11 (Box 31, Folder 30)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Equipment, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Follow-up Possibilities, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Population Council, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Khavari, Khalil, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Kiancher, Mrs. Jeanette, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Knight, Douglas M., 1975 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Krause, Richard M., 1975 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Kunkel, Henry, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Kunstadt, Herbert, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Library, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Linen, James, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Loeb, John, 1974-1977 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: McMichael, Sir John, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Mehr, Farhang, 1974-1976 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Mofedi, Shamseddin, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Morton, Byron B., 1975 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Motamedi, Ghassem, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Nasr, Dr. Khosrow, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Procurement, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Sabin, Albert B., 1975 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Samii, Abdol, Hossein, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Samiy, Fatola, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Seldin, Donald W., MD, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: "Talent Search" [Iranians in the U.S.], 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 24)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Thank yous/March Trip, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 25)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Thank you letters and Replies, 1974-1975 (Box 32, Folder 26)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Trip, 1975 March (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Trip, 1975 March (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Trips, 1975 April-May (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Trips, 1974 November-1975 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: U.S. Contacts/Consultants, 1974-1976 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Vafai, Changiz, 1976 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Zahedi, Ardeshir, 1974-1975 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Iran Files - A-Z: Zarghamee, Dr. Mehdi S., 1975 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Iran Files: Reports, 1975 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Iran Files: "A Review of Biomedical Research in Reproduction Biology in Countries of the Developing World" [Bound Report], 1970-1973 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Iran Files: "University Development Education for Development Program Review" [Bound Copy], 1975 October 14 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Iran Files: "Academic Planning Report Prepared for the Trustees of Reza Shah Kabir University" [Bound Copy], 1975 July (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files: "Site Planning Report Prepared for the Trustees of Reza Shah Kabir University" [Bound Copy], 1975 July (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files: Articles & Clippings I, 1968-1974 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files: Articles & Clippings II, 1974-1976 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files: Articles & Clippings III, 1974-1975 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files: Articles & Clippings IV, 1975-1976 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Iran Files: Report to Imperial Government of Iran [On the Feasibility of Establishing A New Biomedical Research Institute], 1975 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Iran Files: Lushbough, Charming/Expenses, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Iran Files: Photos, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Iran Files: Feasibility Study Plans, 1974-1976 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Iran Files: Report Outline [Outline for a Feasibility Study on the Establishment of a Superior Research Institute in Iran], 1975 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Iran Files: RWN Correspondence/Memos, 1968 1972 1974-1977 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Iran Files: Others - Correspondence/Memos [FS, DR, James Linen, etc], 1974-1977 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Iran Files: Admin. Personnel, 1975 (Box 35, Folder 7)